Okay, so
let's get back to computer systems.
This is where I think I'm going to have to
restart the computer because in
installing operating systems we
now enter point six of the
installation procedure.
But before that, let's
talk about virtualization technologies
for performing a
001 installation, an
operating system installation.
First of all,
okay?  First of all,
what we have to do is download an
installation media.  Generally
today the default medium
is an ISO image.
The ISO image, the old
installation DVD,
can be downloaded from the web.
For example, in the case of Uguntu,
well, okay, we download Ugun Desktop
and we can download it, we can get it
here.  In the case of Windows,
in the case of Windows,
uh, download Windows 11.
download Windows 11. We can
download it from this URL.
Once we've downloaded, okay?  Once
we've
downloaded it,
either we burn it
to an installation DVD
or we generate removable installation media
.
For example, with Rufus we can
generate a USB installer.
Okay,
but of course, the problem is that if
I download one now and click install,
what's going to happen is that I'm going to
crash my computer, okay?
Generally,
virtualization is used to test operating systems.
Virtualization and now we're going to
virtualization technologies, okay?  And
now we'll go back to installation 001
introduction.md,
okay?
Uh, virtualization
allows us to emulate one computer system
within another.
We create a virtual machine
with characteristics
equal to or inferior
to the physical machine.
And on that virtual machine
we perform
an installation.
Recommended software.
Oracle Virtual Box.   Let's
go for it.  Let's go to Virtual Box.
Oracle Virtual Box.  I'm going to put the
website here, okay?  And we are going to
download.  Once we download it,
we install it.  In my case, I already
have it downloaded.  You have it for
Windows, for Mac, for Linux,
for Solaris, right?  So once
we've downloaded the virtual machine,
I'm going to go to Virtual Box.  Wait a minute,
I'm going to close things.
What was this?
Nothing.  Ah, yes, out.  Okay.  Okay.  Okay,
I'm going to go to the virtual machine,
sorry.  I'm going to go to Virtual Box,
okay?  And I'm going to, in this case, I'm going to
delete this machine, delete all
the files, and I'm going to create a new
virtual machine.  Let's see it.
Okay.  And operations.  First new
virtual machine
and this one was a new one.  What
features will it have?  Well,
name, Uguntu Linux.
Name Uguntu Linux.
image.  Well, I think I must have
some
downloaded already.
This out.
Let's see.  Ubun.
I should have some of this, okay?  For
example.
Okay.  And
desktop and I put it here.  Why does it
appear twice?  Don't know.  Okay.  And
ISO image.  I select an image and take
the Ugundu image.
ISO image.  Selected image,
downloaded
from the internet.
Type Linux version Ubuntu, okay?  Type
Linux version Ubuntu.
Unattended installation, skip.  Okay, I
don't want unattended installation, I
want to install it myself.  Hardware, of course,
if I have 16 GB, then I'm going to give it 4192,
okay?  Hardware,
if I have 16 GB, I'm going to give it 4 GB, okay?
one/4
CPUs.  If I have 20 I'm going to give him four.   I
mean, I give it, okay, a
hard drive part, so I'm going to give it 125 GB.   Just
because I give it 125 GB doesn't mean that
at the moment I create it it will take
a 125 GB chunk of my physical hard drive
unless I give it the option to
reserve it completely, which I'm not going to
give it, of course.  So I
click on finish.
I click on finish
and then I'll click on start.   The thing is,
I think at
this particular moment I'll have to
restart the computer for a moment because it
seems like I have something disabled on
the motherboard.  Okay, just a moment, I'm going to
hit start
and boom, sure enough.  Okay, I have an
error on the motherboard.
So, KVM extension.
Just a second, give me a second to
make sure.
Let's see.
No, GPT chat, this is GPT chat, eh,
Virtual Boxtu
on
error.
Let's see for
a moment because, well, some of you
will get similar errors.
And let's see what I can do
because it tells me that it cannot operate in
VMX root mode.   It
tells me to disable the
KVM kernel extension,
but recompiling the kernel has its
dangers, obviously, so I'm going to
see if there's an easier way
to activate the virtual machine without
having to recompile the
kernel, which as I said, by making
this work,
other things could stop working, which
obviously we don't want.
Okay, just a second.
Okay, another hypervisor.
Yes, but there is no other hypervisor.
No,
KVM is loaded.  Okay,
come on.
Okay.
Intel.
And wait a moment.  And wait a moment.  Let's see.
Okay, just a moment because I'm going to
reboot.
Don't leave the room because
I'll be back in now, but before that, I
have to restart to apply
these changes, okay?  So stay
here.  Okay.